<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">


  
  <h3>Data Entry Personnel</h3> <a name="data-entry-personnel"/>
  The Data Entry Personnel human actor is the health worker responsible for entering in health event data into a Point of Care system under retrospective data entry.

  <h3>National Public Key Directory (NPKD)</h3>  <a name="npkd"> </a>
  The National Public Key Directory system actor is a national public key directory which shares the public keys used within the Member State's jurisidiction.

  <h3>WHO Public Key Directory (WHO-PKD)</h3>  <a name="whopkd"> </a>
  The WHO Public Key Directory system actor is a quality-controlled, global master list of public keys, revocation lists, and internet endpoints that operationalize the trust network between Member States’ PHAs.

  <h3>Point of Care</h3>  <a name="point-of-care"> </a>
  The Point of Care system actor is responsible for recording vaccination events either during a clinical encounter by a Vaccinator or during retrospective data entry by a Data Clerk.   It is recommended that the Point of Care system actor should:
  <ul>
    <li>be authorized by the Public Health Authority to record vaccination events</li>
    <li>establish that the Vaccinator is authorized by the Public Health Authority to perform the requested vaccinations</li>
  </ul>


  <h3>Smart Health Certificate (SHC) Generator</h3>  <a name="shc-generator"> </a>
  The SHC Generator system actor is responsible for signing Smart Health Certificates and delivering these to the approriate system actors.  Specifically the SHC Generator should receving health event content from a Point of Care system and:
  <ul>
    <li>generate a signed QR code representing the health event and returning to the Point of Care system</li>
    <li>generate a signed FHIR Document representing the health event and registering it with the SHC Registry Service</li>
  </ul>


  <h3>Smart Health Certiciate (SHC) Holder</h3>  <a name="shc-holder"> </a>
  The SHC Holder human actor represents the person who is responsible for holding the the Smart Health Certificate on behalf of the Subject of Care. The SHC Holder may or may not be the same actor as teh Subject of Care.


  <h3>Smart Health Certificate (SHC) Registry Service</h3>  <a name="shc-registry"> </a>
  The SHC Registry Service system actor is reponsible for recording registration of a Smart Health Certificate and supporting future retrieval or verification of Smart Health Certificates.
   
  <h3>Subject of Care</h3>  <a name="subject-of-care"> </a>
  The Subject of Care human actor is the primary subject of the health event being recording in the SHC.

  <h3>Vaccinator</h3>  <a name="vaccinator"/>
  The Vaccinator human actor is the health worker that performs the vaccination.  The Vaccinator may, though is not required to, record vaccination event data into the Point of Care system during a clinical encounter. 

  <h3>Verfier</h3><a name="verifier"/>
  The Verifier human actor verifies a claim represented by a Smart Health Certificate.
</div>
