<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  
  <h3 id="data-entry-personnel">Data Entry Personnel</h3> 
  <p>The Data Entry Personnel human actor is the health worker responsible for entering in health event data into a Point of Care system under retrospective data entry.</p>

  <h3 id="ddcc-generator">DDCC:VS Generation Service</h3>	
  <p>The service that is responsible for generating a digitally signed representation, the DDCC, of the information concerning a COVID-19 vaccination.</p>

  <h3 id="ddcc-holder">DDCC:VS Holder</h3>	
  <p>The person who has the Subject of Care’s vaccination certificate. The person is usually the Subject of Care but does not have to be. For example, a caregiver may hold the DDCC:VS for a child or other dependant.</p>

  <h3 id="ddcc-registry">DDCC:VS Registry Service</h3>	
  <p>The service that can be used to request and receive the digitally signed COVID-19 vaccination information.</p>

  <h3 id="ddcc-repository">DDCC:VS Repository Service</h3>	
  <p>A potentially federated service that has a repository, or database, of DDCC:VS.</p>

  <h3 id="digital-health-solution">Digital Health Solution</h3>	
  <p>A secure system that is used at the point of care or health facility, such as an electronic immunization registry (EIR), an electronic medical record or a shared health record (SHR).</p>

  <h3 id="public-health-authority">Public Health Authority (PHA)</h3>	
  <p>An entity or organization under whose auspices the vaccination is performed and the DDCC:VS is issued.</p>

  <h3 id="subject-of-care">Subject of Care</h3>	
  <p>The vaccinated person.</p>

  <h3 id="vaccinator ">Vaccinator</h3>	
  <p>The person who administers the vaccine. Depending on national policies, the person who administers the vaccine might not be a formal health-care provider. Examples include physicians, nurse practitioners, community health workers or volunteer vaccinators.</p>

  <h3 id="verifier">Verifier</h3>	
  <p>A natural person or legal person, either private or public, formally authorized (under national law, decree, regulation or other official act or order) to verify the vaccination status presented on the DDCC.</p>

</div>
