<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" lang="en">
  <a name="scope">  </a>

      
  
  <p>
    This is the FHIR Implementation Guide for WHO Digital Documentation of COVID-19 Certificates: Vaccination Status (DDCC:VS).
  </p>

  <blockquote class="stu-note">
    <ul>
      <li>The published version of this IG can be found at:  https://WorldHealthOrganization.github.io/ddcc</li>
      <li>   <strong>This implementation guide and set of artifacts are still undergoing development.</strong> </li>
      <li>DDCC:VS includes key business requirements for a digital vaccination certificate (Digital Documentation of COVID-19 Certificates, DDCC) for national adoption that includes the prioritized scenarios of use, use cases, key workflows, a core data set mapped to a preferred code system, and this FHIR Implementation Guide for the DDCC:VS scope. The first release candidate also begins to outline a global trust framework and high-level overview of a governance mechanism.</li>
      <li>   This content is only for demonstration purposes only. </li>
    </ul>
  </blockquote>
  

  <h3>Summary</h3> <a name="summary"> </a>


  <p>
    This Implementation Guide contains the full set of specifications for the DDCC:VS.
  </p>
  

  <p>
    This Implementation Guide is underpinned by supporting <a href="references.html">guidelines, policies and recommendations</a>
  </p>
  


  <h3>About This Implementation Guide</h3> <a name="about"> </a>
  
  <p>
    This Implementation Guide is broken into the following levels of <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/cpg/2019Sep/documentation-approach.html">knowledge representation</a>:
    <ul>
      <li><a href="index.html">Narrative</a> Contains references to the guidance, guidelines, policies and recommemndations underpinning this Implementation Guide</li>
      <li><a href="requirements.html">Business Requirements</a> Contains the requirements for this Implementation Guide including the defintition of key concepts, user personas, use cases and workflows.
      </li>
      <li><a href="data_exchange.html">Data Models and Exchange</a> Contains the data models and data exchange protocols defined in this Implementation Guide.</li>
      <li><a href="deployment.html">Deployment Guidance </a>
      Contains technical specifications and guidance relevant to this Implementation Guide and supporting guidance for adaptation in local environments.</li>
    </ul>
  </p>  



  <h3>Disclaimer</h3>  <a name="disclaimer"> </a>
  <p>
    The specification herewith documented is a demo working specification, and may not be used for any implementation purposes. 
    This draft is provided without warranty of completeness or consistency, and the official publication supersedes this draft.
    No liability can be inferred from the use or misuse of this specification, or its consequences.
  </p>
</div>  
