<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" lang="en">
  <a name="scope">  </a>

      
  
  <p>
    This is the FHIR Implementation Guide for WHO Smart Vaccination Certificate (SVC).
  </p>

  <blockquote class="stu-note">
    <ul>

      <li>   <strong>This implementation guide and set of artifacts are still undergoing development.</strong> </li>
      <li>   This content is only for demonstration purposes only. </li>
    </ul>
  </blockquote>
  

  <h3>Summary</h3> <a name="summary"> </a>


  <p>
    This Implementation Guide contains the full set of specifications for Release Candidate 2 (RC2) of the WHO Smart Vaccination Certificate (SVC). 
  </p>
  

  <p>
    This Implmentation Guide is underpinned by supporting <a href="references.html">guidelines, policies and recommendations</a>
  </p>
  


  <h3>About This Implemention Guide</h3> <a name="about"> </a>
  
  <p>
    This Implementation Guide is broken into the following levels of <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/cpg/2019Sep/documentation-approach.html">knowledge representation</a>:
    <ul>
      <li><a href="index.html">Narrative</a> Contains references to the guidance, guidlines, policies and recommemndations underpinning this Implementation Guide</li>
      <li><a href="requirements.html">Business Requirements</a> Contains the requirements for this Implementation Guide including the defintition of key concepts, user personas, use cases and workflows.
      </li>
      <li><a href="data_exchange.html">Data Models and Exchange</a> Contains the data models and data exchange protocles defined in this Implementation Guide.</li>
      <li><a href="deployment.html">Deployment Guidance </a>
      Contains technical specfications and guidance relevant to this Implemenation Guide and supporting guidance for adaptation in local environments.</li>
    </ul>
  </p>  



  <h3>Disclaimer</h3>  <a name="disclaimer"> </a>
  <p>
    The specification herewith documented is a demo working specification, and may not be used for any implementation purposes. 
    This draft is provided without warranty of completeness or consistency, and the official publication supersedes this draft.
    No liability can be inferred from the use or misuse of this specification, or its consequences.
  </p>
</div>  
