<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

  <p style="background-color: #ffefef; border:1px solid maroon; padding: 5px;max-width: 790px;">
    For the latest published definitions, refer to the Digital Documentation of COVID-19 Certificates guidance.
  </p>
  
  <p>The scope of this implementation guide covers two scenarios of use for the DDCC:VS:></p>

  <ol>
    <li><b>CONTINUITY OF CARE:</b> Vaccination records are an important part of an individual’s medical records, starting at birth. The Continuity of Care scenario describes the primary purpose of a vaccination certificate. The vaccination record shows individuals and caregivers which vaccinations an individual has received, as part of that individual’s medical history; it therefore supports informed decision-making on any future health service provision.</li>
    <li><b>PROOF OF VACCINATION:</b> Vaccination records can also provide proof of vaccination status for purposes not related to health care.</li>
  </ol>

  <h3 id="use-case-care">Continuity of Care</h3> <a name="use-case-care"> </a>
  <p>In the context of COVID-19, the use of a vaccination record for Continuity of Care is primarily to: ensure that individuals know if, and when, they will need a subsequent dose; for health workers to use the proof of COVID-19 vaccination to decide on provision of health services based on medical history; and for ensuring health workers have access to accurate vaccination history when an adverse event follows immunization. It will be up to Member States to define how this scenario is applied and adapted to their own context and level of digital maturity, in compliance with their legal and policy frameworks.</p> 
  <table class="list">
    <tr><th width="100">Use case ID</th><th width="120">Use case name</th><th>Use case description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>UC001</td><td>Paper first</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded on paper. After the vaccination event, data about it can be entered into a Digital Health Solution.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC002</td><td>Offline digital</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an offline secure Digital Health Solution, with the content uploaded, subsequently, to an online Digital Health Solution.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC003</td><td>Online digital</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an online secure Digital Health Solution which updates the content in real time.</td></tr>
  </table>

  <h3 id="use-case-proof">Proof of Vaccination</h3> <a name="use-case-proof"> </a>  

  <table class="list">
    <tr><th width="100">Use case ID</th><th width="120">Use case name</th><th>Use case description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>UC006</td><td>Manual verification</td><td>A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using purely visual means, based on his or her subjective judgement, as is currently done with International Certificate of Vaccination or Prophylaxis. This type of check is currently well accepted, is quick and easy to do, and requires no digital technology.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC007</td><td>Offline cryptographic verification</td><td>A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an offline mode.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC008</td><td>Online status check (national DDCC:VS)</td><td>This pathway is used when the DDCC:VS is being verified in the same jurisdiction as it was issued. A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an online mode that includes a status check against the PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry Service and optionally the DDCC:VS Repository.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC009</td><td>Online status check (international DDCC:VS)</td><td>This pathway is used when the DDCC:VS is being verified in a foreign jurisdiction to where it was issued. A Verifier verifies an internationally issued DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an online mode that includes a status check against the National PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry Service, which in turn accesses an International PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry and DDCC:VS Repository, if such services exist and such access is authorized by the issuing PHA. It is assumed in this workflow that a Verifier does not directly access an International PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry or Repository Service.</td></tr>
  </table>

</div>
