<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

  <p style="background-color: #ffefef; border:1px solid maroon; padding: 5px;max-width: 790px;">
    For the latest published definitions, refer to the Digital Documentation of COVID-19 Certificates guidance.
  </p>
  
  <h3>Continuity of Care</h3> <a name="coc"> </a>
  <table>
    <tr><td>UC001</td><td>Paper first</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded on paper. After the vaccination event, data about it can be entered into a Digital Health Solution.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC002</td><td>Offline digital</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an offline secure Digital Health Solution, with the content uploaded, subsequently, to an online Digital Health Solution.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC003</td><td>Online digital</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an online secure Digital Health Solution which updates the content in real time.</td></tr>
  </table>

  <h3>Proof of Vaccination</h3> <a name="proof"> </a>  

  <table>
    <tr><th>Use case ID</th><th>Use case name</th><th>Use case description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>UC006</td><td>Manual verification</td><td>A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using purely visual means, based on his or her subjective judgement, as is currently done with International Certificate of Vaccination or Prophylaxis. This type of check is currently well accepted, is quick and easy to do, and requires no digital technology.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC007</td><td>Offline cryptographic verification</td><td>A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an offline mode.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC008</td><td>Online status check (national DDCC:VS)</td><td>This pathway is used when the DDCC:VS is being verified in the same jurisdiction as it was issued. A Verifier verifies a DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an online mode that includes a status check against the PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry Service and optionally the DDCC:VS Repository.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC009</td><td>Online status check (international DDCC:VS)</td><td>This pathway is used when the DDCC:VS is being verified in a foreign jurisdiction to where it was issued. A Verifier verifies an internationally issued DDCC:VS using digital cryptographic processes in an online mode that includes a status check against the National PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry Service, which in turn accesses an International PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry and DDCC:VS Repository, if such services exist and such access is authorized by the issuing PHA. It is assumed in this workflow that a Verifier does not directly access an International PHA’s DDCC:VS Registry or Repository Service.</td></tr>
  </table>

  
</div>
