<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">


  <h3>Continuity of Care</h3> <a name="coc"> </a>
  <table>
    <tr><td>UC001</td><td>Paper first</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded entirely on paper, with the digital content captured later (as a “back data entry” workflow) and uploaded to the Public Health Authority (PHA).</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC002</td><td>Offline digital health</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an offline digital health solution with the content uploaded, subsequently, to the PHA.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC003</td><td>Online digital health</td><td>A guideline-based vaccine administration is recorded using an online digital health solution which updates the content, in real time, to the PHA.</td></tr>
  </table>

  <img src="coc.png" />

  <h3>Proof of Vaccination</h3> <a name="proof"> </a>  
  <img src="pov.png"/>

  <table>
    <tr><th>Use case ID</th><th>Use case name</th><th>Use case description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>UC006</td><td>Manual verification</td><td>A verifier verifies an SVC using purely manual (visual) means.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC007</td><td>Offline cryptographic verification</td><td>A verifier verifies an SVC, using digital cryptographic processes, in an offline mode.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC008</td><td>Online status check (national SVC)</td><td>A verifier verifies an SVC, using digital cryptographic processes, in an online mode that includes a status check against the public health authority’s SVC Registry.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>UC009</td><td>Online status check (international SVC)</td><td>A verifier verifies an internationally issued SVC, using digital cryptographic processes, in an online mode that includes a status check against the national public health authority’s SVC Registry, which in turn accesses the international public health authority’s SVC Registry.</td></tr>
  </table>

  
</div>
